I think Bitcoin has been a sort-of  holding pattern for last year or so.
私が思うにビットコインは、この1年ほど、 飛行機の空中待機のような状態にいると思います。
As people try to figure out whether the problem Bitcoin has encountered can be resolved
ビットコインがいま遭遇している問題を解決できるかどうか、
Or whether you are going to need to  move to some other system
もしくは、ビットコインが約束したメリットを
to get the benefits that Bitcoin promised
他のブロックチェインを使ったシステムで得るために、 そちらに移動する必要があるかどうか。
TRUST DISRUPTED BITCOIN AND THE BLOCKCHAIN TechCrunch Originals
TRUST破砕 ビットコインとブロックチェイン TechCrunchのオリジナル
IV. Blockchain on the Rise
４．ブロックチェインの趨勢
$350 Million: value of Bitcoins lost in 2013 bankruptcy of Mt.Gox
350億円：マウントゴックス社の倒産で減ったビットコインの価値
$65 Million: value of Bitcoins lost in 2016 hack of Bitfinex
65億円； ビットフィネックス社へのハッキングで減ったビットコインの価値
Consensus Conference May 2,2016 New York
ニューヨーク コンセンサス会議（ブロックチェーンの国際会議） 2016年5月2日
a few hours after computer scientist Craig wright declares he's Satoshi Nakamoto
コンピューター科学者のクレイグ・ライトが 自分がサトシ・ナカモトであると発表した2時間後。
You were saying it doesn’t matter that Satoshi is Craig Wright ?
クレイグ・ライトでサトシナカモトであっても ご自分には関係ないことだと言っていましたか？
Yeah, I don’t think he has that  much power,
ええ、私は、彼に多くの力があるとは思いません。
Back before the announcement,
発表がある前でも、
I thought it was one person because you know
私は、サトシナカモトとは個人だと考えていました。
honestly  people think it is secretly  massive achievement
正直、人々は、ビットコインがすごく隠された巨大な成果で 複数の人がかかわっていただと考えていますが、
But it just was hitting at the right thing and at a right time.
しかし、私は、ビットコインが、たまたま、ちょうどいいタイミングの ちょうどいいモノであったというだけだと思います。
I thought it was just someone,you know, random 30 to50 year old male ,quite possibly Japanese.
彼が 30代～40代のどこかの男性で。恐らく日本人なんだろうなと。
** supposed to be Japanese **
**
VITALIK BUTERIN , FOUNDER, ETHEREUM,TORONTO,MOSCOW,SHANGHAI So I discover the Bitcoin back in  2011
ヴィタリク・ブテリン、イーサリアムの創業者、トロント、モスクワ、上海 僕は、2011年にビットコインと出会いました。
Actually , First time I heard about it  my Dad told me. And he said,
初めて聞いたのは、僕のパパからです。
It's very interesting new currency. It is not issued by any kind of government and de-centralized.
彼が、言ってたのは、それが、かなり面白い新しい通貨だということ。 政府からは発行されておらず、しかも分散化されているんだよと。
I should check it out.
僕は調べなきゃと思いました。
I started to work seriously getting on the floor I was trying to earn bitcoins myself by just writing articles on various different blogs.
それから 真剣に関わりはじめ、様々なブログに 記事を書くことでビットコインを自分で稼いでいました。
Eventually I started to get  more and more into it and I ended up  co-founding a Bitcoin magazine.
最終的に、私はそれに、どんどんのめりこみ、 最後は、ビットコインマガジンを 共同設立しました。
So in High-tech,  we talk about networking effect
ハイテクの世界では、我々は よく ネットワーク効果について話します。
like e-bay had fantastic network effect
たとえばイーベイは、最高のネットワーク効果の恩恵を受けました。
there are  two sides, buyers and sellers , people auctioning stuff.
そこには2種類の人がいます。 買い手と売り手ですね。ものをオークションで売りたい人々と
and people wanna buy a stuff.
ものを購入したい人たちです。
The bigger the market places,The more buyers you attract, the more buyers there are  The more people sell there.
市場がより大きければ大きいほど、 あなたが引き付けることができる買い手が多ければ多いほど、 そこに来てくれる買い手が多ければ多いほど、より多くの売り手がそこに集まります。
That's network effect.
これがネットワーク効果です。
eBay is the 800 pound gorilla.
イーベイは、ネットオークションの世界では、 巨大なゴリラみたいな存在です。
In the crypt currency space,right now Bitcoins is the 800 pound gorilla.
暗号化通貨の世界では、今のビットコインが巨大なゴリラといえるでしょう。
In terms of technological proof of concept, it is  inspired developers around the world
技術的な概念実証の観点で、世界中の開発者だけでなく
financial institutions, governments, stock exchanges, pretty much everybody doing anything in financial services.
金融機関、政府機関、証券取引所、- 金融サービスでなにかを行っている機関が、ビットコインに触発され、
has paid attention to the technological achievement
その技術的な成果に注目を向けました。
the currency and *the store* value *less*
**
Blockchain technology that Bitcoin introduced has been eclipsing the original application of blockchain ,Bitcoin.
ブロクックチェーン技術はその最初のアプリケーションである ビットコインに影を落とすようになってきました。
At the end of 2013, people are getting  interested in blockchain technology
2013年の終わりごろ、人々はブロックチェイン技術に興味を持ち始めました
they are getting interested in this idea particularly you can  use it for the application other than Bitcoin.
特にビットコイン以外にブロックチェイン技術を応用するアイデアに 特に興味持ち始めたのです。
Bitcoin currency and Blockchain technology are 2 different things.
ビットコイン通貨とブロックチェイン技術は、2つの異なるものですからね。
Snapcard Founded 2013 San Francisco
Snapcard サンフランシスコ 2013設立
Mission Statement: Make it easier for consumers and businesses to use blockchain technologies
ミッションステートメント： 消費者や企業がブロックチェイン技術を簡単に利用できるようにします
World can change completely based on what this technology can do
世界は、この技術で実現できる様々なもののおかげで、 完全に変わる可能性があります。
It is like an alien technology basicaly like  we've never have it  before
これはまるで宇宙から来た技術のようです。 いままで誰も持った事が無かった。
Now we've  gotten everyone rushing to play with it.
そしていま、あらゆる人が 、それ使ってみようと大忙しです。
I think that's what's exciting about it
私はそれがとてもエキサイティングなことだと思います。
if you look at for different developers like build products
例えば、製品開発をする プログラマーを調べてみるとわかりますが、
They always wanna like to try out new cool stuff.
彼らは いつも 新しいく クールなものを試してみたいと思っています。
if they are building before before the internet,building software. started building web pages which is really  cool.
インターネットの前であれば、彼らは、ソフトウェアを作成し、 そして次に クールであったWebページを構築し始めました。
and then started to build web applications
そして、Webアプリケーションを構築し始め、
mobile got much more cool
モバイルアプリが、はるかにクールになり
more challenging or  more new mobile instead of web
すなわち、ウェブアプリより、さらに挑戦的で 新しい。
I think that blockchain is kind-of that next step.
そして、私は　ブロックチェーンが　その次のステップになると思います。
Consensus 2016, may 2-4, 2016 Making Blockchain Real New York City
コンセンサスカンファレｒンス　2016月2月4日 ブロックチェーンを現実に ニューヨークシティ
So 1.1 billion dollars has been raised today
現在、1100億円が、暗号通貨とブロックチェーンの
by  cryptcurrency and blockchain start-ups
スタートアップに投資されています。
That's really really significant number
こは本当にかなりの数字であります。
The other point that is interesting with Q1 especially that we saw a reversal of the trend
また、面白いポイントは、トータルの投資量と平均投資額の両方の視点で、
has been declining level of investment in the industry of last several quarters both in terms of overall fund flow and average deal size
去年の4半期では、投資が減少傾向にありましたが、
This really changed in Q1 with emergence of blockchain is the distinct investment category.
今年の第一四半期、投資のカテゴリーである、ブロックチェーンの 登場とともに、大きく、変わり始めました。
Identity Mind Global is a provider of risk management services.
アイデンティティ・マインド・グローバルです。 当社は、リスクマネジメントサービスのプロバイダーです。
We see a blockchain really as a new medium for financial asset
私たちは ブロックチェーンを、 金融資産のための新しい媒体として見ています。
t0 is a platform for exchanging digital assets which we've created using a blockchain technology It specialized to exchange. ...
我々の会社 ティーゼロ　は、デジタル資産 を交換するためのプラットフォームです。 ブロックチェーン技術を使用して作成しており、、、、
Having to have a piece of plastic and you gotta remember with you. what you can do is you could use your mobile device
プラスチックのクレジットカードを利用するばあい、それを忘れず持ち歩かないといけません。 我々のサービスを使えば、あなたのモバイルデバイスを使って支払をすることができます。
We especially started with Bitcoin blockchain,public blockchain. We are gonna move now next to Etherium public blockchain. eventually connects to multiple blockchains.
我々は、特にビットコインブロックチェイン、公共ブロックチェインから始めました。 私たちは今、公共ブロックチェーンをイーサリウムに移行しようとしています。 最終的には複数のブロックチェーンに接続できる計画です。
We are build a proof of concept
私たちは、概念実証のためのシステムを構築しています。
decentralize the energy company
電力会社の分散化で、
that connects neighbors in the rural environment
田舎の環境で隣人同志を接続し、
and counts the consumption and production of electricity
と電気の消費量と生産量をカウントします。
on the block chain
ブロックチェーン上でね。
Satoshi and Craig Wright, the news about who Satoshi is
サトシとクレイグ・ライトのニュースですが、
Do you believe Craig Wright and does it matter ?
あなたはクレイグ・ライトが言ったことを信じますか？ そして、それはあなたに 関係しそうですか？
I am  Satoshi,   I am kidding.
私がサトシです。。。 冗談です。
Does it matter to me or to us ?  I don’t know , I guess not.
それが、私や私たちに関係あるかですか？どうかなー。多分ないね。
We refer to ourselves as   Bitcoin agnostic.
私たちは、ビットコイン不可知論者として自分達を見ています。
If Bitcoin finds itself successful , Great. If Bitcoin doesn’t find itself successful ,that's  Great. I doesn’t impact what we are trying to do.
ビットコインが成功したシステムと認められた場合、すばらしい。 ビットコインが成功したシステムとして認められない場合、それも素晴らしいです。 私たちがやろうとしているものには影響しません。
I think here we are pretty agnostic , in terms of which one is the one.
私たちはそのブロックチェーンが一番素晴らしいかどうかに関しては、 特に 意見はありません。
when companies are fighting for your eyeballs using blockchain tech
あらゆる企業が 注目を浴びようと、ブロックチェイン技術を使って
competing blockchain tech. That's really what it *starts*.
争っています。まだ始まったばかりです。
Right now everyone is still building  cars to start a race
今、誰もが、まだレースを開始するための車を作っている状態です。
Everyone still ,you know , this is in development .you know, Barclays got this program. They got this programing like Common Wealth Bank.
誰もが、まだ、開発中の状態です。 バークレイズ銀行では、こんなブロックチェーンシステムをつくりました。 コモンウェルス銀行でが　こんなシステムを作りました、とか。
All these big institutions are starting to build places and dedicated  block chain labs have these all these people  getting the resources and money get throwing at tit.
これらすべての大きな企業が 専用のブロックチェーン研究ラボを作ったり、 リソースとお金を投入し始めています。
I am not saying that those guys are gonna be the reason why we all feel it  but
私は、 大企業が 参入し始めているのが理由で ワクワクしていると 言ってるのではありませんよ。
might be a bunch of  hackers sitting in the bed room  that  make something really awesome.
もしかしたら ベッドルームで座って プログラミングしてる ハッカー達が本当にすごいものを作り、
that  change your life And that could be it.
それが、あなたの人生を変える可能性もあります。
I don't know We will wait and see.
どうなるかわわかりません。時間が教えてくれるでしょう。
Beyond that, there is the Etherium vision
ビットコインを超えた、新しいブロックチェインである エーサリウムのビジョンが あります。
This isn't just going to be  a place for financial transactions.
これは単に金融取引のための場所ではありません。
THis is going to be how basicaly  organizations and  informational flow around the world happens as well
これは、世界規模での 組織と情報の流れが どう行われるかというものになります。
In some way It's more ambitious.
ある意味、ビットコインよりも、さらに野心的です。
That's a vision of the future in which you essentially have enormous global computer
未来に関するビジョンであります。 それは、世界中にちらばっりネットワークでつながったコンピューターを使うことであり、
on which all of software and decision making and political processes can run.
そして、そこの上で あらゆるソフトウエアや意思決定や政治的プロセスが実行できるということです。